# Tomi Aina . Jarvis Consulting

I currently work as a software developer with Jarvis consulting, where I work on different projects on Linux cluster management, Java applications, spring boot REST API, and others. I am also completing a Ph.D. in Electrical Engineering. My research is focused on using computer vision techniques to diagnose cervical cancer lesions found in females. I am proficient in data analysis and providing insights to businesses using data. I have experience teaching undergraduate and postgraduate student.

#### Skills

Proficient: Java, Linux/Bash, RDBMS/SQL, Agile/Scrum, Git

Competent: Pandas, Scikit-learn, Machine Learning, Deep Learning, Data Analysis

Familiar: Google Cloud Platform, MATLAB, Computer Networking, Technical Writing, JAVA

## Jarvis Projects

Project source code: https://github.com/jarviscanada/jarvis\_data\_eng\_TomiAina

Cluster Monitor [GitHub]: Implemented a Minimum Viable Product (MVP) that stores each server/node's hardware specifications and monitors resource usage (e.g. CPU usage) in real-time. The data is stored in an RDBMS database (PostgreSQL) which can be used for reporting and, in the future, resource planning.

#### **Highlighted Projects**

**Development of a deep-learning based cervical screening system:** Developed a Computer Vision-based-system that can detect cervical cancer lesions using a mobile phone. A mobile application is developed that can automatically screen cervix images in real-time. It was designed to aid screening, particularly in low-resource regions and could potentially reduce the prevalence of cervical cancer in these regions.

Optimization of Household Energy Management System: Developed a Household Energy Management System that aims to minimize customers' electricity bills by predicting the operation time of appliances in the home.

#### Professional Experiences

Software Developer, Jarvis (2020-present): Worked on various projects such as Linux cluster monitoring, Twitter CRUD App, SpringBoot amongst others

**Program Instructor, Nile University of Nigeria (2019-2020)**: Developed curriculum and taught courses in machine learning, introduction to Electrical Engineering and computer programming. Led the team involved in transitioning the team from physical and online school during the pandemic in 2019. Involved in a couple of administrative and accreditation exercises in the Faculty.

Data Scienetist, KETT Automobile (2016-2017): Provided strategic insight to the business based on past data on best practices in reducing utility bills and investment diversification of the company.

### Education

Nile University of Nigeria (2018-2021), Doctor of Philosphy, Electrical Engineering - Obtained a 5.0/5.0 GPA in the first year of PhD

The University of Birmingham (2014-2018), Master of Science, Electrical and Computer Engineering

Covenant University (2009-2014), Bachelors of Engineering, Electrical and Electronics Engineering

#### Miscellaneous

- CISCO Certified Network Associate
- Home Reno and Interior
- Teaching Kids